

☑ l.callot@gmail.com | 🎓 www.lcallot.github.io | 🖸 lcallot | 🛅 lcallot | 🞓 Laurent Callot

## Summary\_

I lead teams working on generative AI and AI Ops at AWS AI Labs. I define the scientific and product strategy at the organization level. I have extensive experience building and managing teams of scientists, ML engineers, and managers distributed across multiple continents.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**AWS AI Labs** Seattle, USA - Berlin, Germany

PRINCIPAL APPLIED SCIENTIST AND MANAGER

Mar. 2020 - current

- · Science leader and manager for Sagemaker generative AI product.
- · Defined the organization's strategy for AI agents and for generative AI verifiability, moderation, and trustworthiness.
- Science leader and manager for Amazon's internal tooling organization Builder Tools.
- · Defined Builder Tools' generative AI strategy. Led the development of a retrieval augmented Q&A system for builders.
- · Led the development of Amazon's deployment safety system monitoring 3 million deployments monthly.
- Hired, grew, and managed teams of scientists and ML engineers distributed over 4 continents.
- · Built and led the team that created and launched an AWS ML anomaly detection service from greenfield.
- Served as principal scientist for 3 other AWS ML services.

### **Amazon.com - Intelligent Cloud Control**

Berlin, Germany

SENIOR APPLIED SCIENTIST

Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- · Science lead for a cross-functional remote team.
- Developed a new alarming system for Amazon's order rates the company's key metric.
- Developed a policy monitoring and incentive scheme for all service owners at Amazon.

### **Amazon.com - Supply Chain Optimization Technology**

Berlin, Germany

**ECONOMIST - SENIOR ECONOMIST** 

Jun. 2016 - Jan. 2019

- Development of Neural Structural models for long-range forecasting
- · Uncertainty quantification of Topline forecasts.

**Danske Commodities**Aarhus, Denmark

**CONSULTANT** 2013 - 2014

· Machine Learning consultant generating price forecasts and trading strategies for the Nordic electricity spot market.

#### **Free University Amsterdam**

Amsterdam, the Netherlands

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER 2012 - 2015

- Researcher on Econometrics and Machine Learning for time-series analysis.
- Research Fellow, the Tinbergen Institute. Junior Research Fellow, CREATES.

### Skills

Management Distributed & cross-functional teams, manager of managers, promotions and underperformance management

**Hiring** 100+ interviews (science, engineering, product), 15+ hires

**Research** 20+ publications on deep-learning, forecasting, anomaly detection, causality, statistics, econometrics.

**Programming** Python, R, LaTeX, Pytorch

**Languages** English (fluent), French (fluent), Danish (proficient)

### Education

### CREATES - Aarhus University

Aarhus, Denmark

Visiting Scholar, Princeton University 2011.

Ph.D. IN ECONOMETRICS (M.Sc. 2009)

**Paris Nanterre University** 

2007 - 2012

• Topics: Time-series, high-dimensional statistics, Machine Learning.

### Paris Sorbonne University - Université Pierre et Marie Curie

Paris, France

B.Sc. IN MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Paris, France

B.Sc. IN ECONOMICS 2007

May 12, 2023 Laurent Callot · Résumé 1